# **VAN TIEN HUNG**

■ D703, Symphony Apartment, Phu My Hung Residence, Street 16, Tan Phu, Dis 7 HCMC

■ Phone: (+84)901.407.955

■ Email: tienhungvan1995@gmail.com



#### **About**

An enthusiastic CFA level II candidate who want to develop career in financial environment. I am well trained to perform financial analysis and modelling data analysis, I am also flexible in teamwork & autonomy. An experienced research analyst in a Fund Management JSC in manufacturing sector. Knowledge and skills in Financial Analysis, Data management and Equity valuation.

### **Work Experiences**

#### Analyst (Oct 2020 - Now)

Oriental Commercial Bank JSC: Performance Management Department

- Data analysis, Compensation and Incentives computing
- Financial Cost controlling
- Risk managing on separate buckets
- Financial modelling and data querying from database with SQL Server
- Management Information System (MIS) and Database tracking

### Financial Analyst (Oct 2019 – Oct 2020)

Technical World Corporation JSC: Financial Accounting Department

- Projects management: Doing Financial Models and Feasibility Reports
- Preparing Loan profiles submitting to Banks, co-operating with banks' officers to complete Bank's Disbursement process.
- Preparing Accounting Management Cash flow Reports submitted to BOD, BOM

#### Equity Research Analyst - Manufacturing sector (June 2018 – Oct 2019)

Phu Hung Fund Management JSC: Research Division

- Writing sector & company reports in cover list, tracking and Updating report periodically. Covering Manufacturing Sector: Materials, Chemicals
- Supporting other department to provide research by request for special purpose (Risk management, Board of Director, Corporation, etc.)
- Monthly joining an investment consultancy in "Giò két sô" program on FBNC Channel.

#### **Education**

#### Master in Data Science

HCMC University of Science – Vietnam (expected graduation in Jan 2023)

#### **Bachelor degree in Finance**

Banking University HCMC – Vietnam (graduated in Aug 2018)

#### **Academic Achievements**

#### **CFA Institute** (Dec 2019)

Passed CFA level 1 exam in Dec 2019.

#### **Banking University HCMC** (Aug 2014 – Aug 2018)

- Excellence scholarship throughout 4 years.
- 2 Scholarships of State Bank of Vietnam
- 1 Scholarship of The Governor of State Bank of Vietnam

## **Extra-curricular Activities**

## **Red Cross** (2014 – now)

Certificate for 5 times Blood-donating

## Skills

#### Verbal

English Proficient

#### Technical

- Microsoft Office, SQL
- Advanced Intermediate
- Excel, Word, Access

Eviews, SPSS, STATAPython, R Basic

#### **Interests**

- Mixology
- Traveling
- Billiard, Archery, Table Tennis, Calligraphy

## **Reference list**

## Dr. Tran Phuc Nguyen - Ph.D. (Finance).

- Lecturer in Finance & Accounting, Banking University University
- Contact Via: Phucnt@buh.edu.vn